Neufeld, Maurice Papers /3007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. XEROX FILES
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 54-60)
    Grievance reports continued from Information Systems Group.
  - Labor Report - I, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 61-66)
    Labor reports of employee rule violations, arranged chronologically
  - Labor Report - II, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 67-72)
    Labor reports of employee rule violations, continued.
  - Labor Report - III, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 73-79)
    Labor reports of employee rule violations
  - Contract - I, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
    Memos from MFN re matters pending in revision of 1973 labor agreement [5/15/74], memo from William Roscoe re contract implementation responsibilities [3/27/74], memorandum of understanding re agreements reached during 1974 contract negotiations, list of Union and Company negotiating committee members [1/15/74], subject index of 1974 contract negotiations, minutes of 1974 contract negotiation meetings [held from 1/8/74 to 2/7/74].
  - Contract - II, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 5-11)
    Minutes of 1974 contract negotiations [held from 2/14/74 to 3/14/74], minutes of contract negotiations held at Cheshire plant [from 1/21/74 to 1/29/74], minutes of contract negotiation meeting held at Irvine plant [8/16/74].
  - Contract - III, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 12-16)
    Company proposals for 1974 contract negotiations.
  - Contract - IV, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 17-23)
    Union demands during 1974 contract negotiations.
  - Contract - V, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 24-30)
    Union demands continued.
  - Contract - VI, 1974-1977 (Box 40, Folder 31-36)
    Final copy of 1974-1977 labor agreement
  - Discipline, Suspension, Discharge, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 37)
    Minutes of disciplinary hearings
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - I, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 38-44)
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 45-50)
    Grievance reports from ISG.
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - III, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 51-53)
    Grievance reports from ISG continued.
  - Labor Report - I, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 54-62)
  - Labor Report - II, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 63-67)
  - Labor Report - III, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 68-75)
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - I, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 1-4)
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 5-9)
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - III, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 10-14)
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports - IV, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 15-17)
  - Labor Report - I, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 18-23)
  - Labor Report - II, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 24-32)
  - Labor Report - III, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 33-38)
  - Labor Report - IV, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 39-46)
  - Arbitration, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 47)
    Copies of arbitration reports.
  - Arbitration - Danno, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 48-52)
    Opinion and award of arbiter in Danno case [9/11/78], final copy of Company brief [6/29/78], Company report including exhibits, earlier drafts of Company brief (with revisions), corres from James Playfair, Industrial Relations at Xerox Corp., to MFN re Danno arbitration case [5/16/78].
  - Arbitration, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 53-57)
    Outline for presentation of arbitration cases [11/7/78], copies of arbiters' opinions and awards, Company reports on arbiitration cases.
  - Arbitration - 9400, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 58-65)
    Corres from Asher to Dana Eischen, Arbitrator, re Company concerns with the outcome of an arbitration hearing [10/18/79], arbiter's opinion and award, Union and Company briefs, Company field investigation report, report on 9400 case (incl. master copy with MFN revisions), fourth step grievance summary, further reports on 9400 case ("9400" refers to 9400 Duplicator assembly line, wherefrom this grievance arose.)
  - Contract - General Negotiation - I, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 1-5)
    Copy of The Digest re terms of newly negotiated 1977 labor agreement [4/29/77], Union proposals for collective bargaining agreement objectives, Company proposals for 1977 contract, minutes of Company-Union contract negotiations [held from 1/13/77 to 3/10/77].
  - Contract - General Negotiation - II, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 6-10)
    Minutes of Company-Union contract negotiations continued [held from 3/11/77 to 3/20/77].
  - Contract - Basic Agreement, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 11-20)
    Early drafts of 1977 labor agreement with revisions and notes.
  - Contract - Agreements Reached, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 21-29)
    Index of agreements reached during contract talks [6/9/77], report of original demands and agreements reached.
  - Contract - Revised Final Agreement, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 30-35)
    Memo from Roscoe to Asher re changes to supplemental agreements to contract [8/25/77], revised final draft of 1977 labor agreement [9/1/77].
  - Contract - Subcommittee - A (Assembly) - MD (Manufacturing Department), 1977 (Box 42, Folder 36-41)
    Minutes of MD Promotion and Transfer Supplement Subcommittee and Maintenance Promotion and Transfer Supplement Subcommittee meetings re Assembly, Fabrication, and Maintenance issues under 1977 contract, drafts of proposals and agreements arising from subcommittee meetings on these issues.
  - Contract - Subcommittee - MM (Materials Manufacturing) - S (Skilled Trades), 1977 (Box 42, Folder 42-48)
    Minutes of MM Promotion and Transfer Supplement Subcommittee and Skilled Trades Subcommittee meetings re issues concerning MM and Skilled Trades under 1977 labor agreement, agreements arising out of these meetings.
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - A, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 49-56)
    Drafts of Supplemental Agreement A to 1977 contract (incl. revisions), agreements reached between Union and Company relative to Supplemental Agreement A.
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - B, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 57-58)
    Drafts and revisions of Supplemental Agreement B to 1977 labor agreement.
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - C, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 59-60)
    Drafts and revisions of Supplemental Agreement C to 1977 labor agreement.
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - D & E, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 61)
    Copies of Supplemental Agreements D and E to 1977 contract.
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - F, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 62)
    Drafts and revisions of Supplemental Agreement F to 1977 contract
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - G, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 63)
    Drafts and revisions of Supplemental Agreement G to 1977 labor agreement.
  - Contract - Supplemental Agreement - H, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 64)
    Drafts and revisions of Supplemental Agreement H to 1977 contract.
  - Contract - Dallas, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 65-69)
    Drafts and revisions of labor agreement and its supplements for Dallas plant
  - Contract - Oklahoma City, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 70-71)
    Copy of contract for Oklahoma City plant (with MFN revisions).
  - Labor Agreement, 1974-1977 (Box 42, Folder 72)
    Printed copy of 1974-1977 Xerox Corp. contract.
  - Labor Agreement, 1977-1980 (Box 42, Folder 73-74)
    Copies of 1977-1980 Xerox Corp. labor agreement.
  - 1980-1983 Agreement - Corporation Demands, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 1-4)
    Report of Company demands prior to 1980 contract negotiations (indexed) [1/13/79], report from William Roscoe re proposed agreement objectives
  - 1980-1983 Agreement - Meetings 1-10 (Box 43, Folder 5-9)
    Minutes of Company-Union contract negotiation meetings [held from 12/14/79 to 2/21/80].
  - 1980-1983 Agreement - Meetings 11-26 (Box 43, Folder 10-15)
    Minutes of Company-Union contract negotiation meetings [held from 3/10/80 to 3/22/80].
  - Labor Agreement - I, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 16-30)
    Summary of agreements reached with regard to Corporation and Union demands
  - Labor Agreement - II, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 31-38)
    Revision of 1977-1980 contract to conform with agreements reached with regard to Corporate and Union demands (first round of revisions).
  - Labor Agreement - III, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 39-49)
    Revision of 1977-80 contract to conform with agreements reached (second and later rounds).
  - Labor Agreement - IV, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 50-69)
    Penultimate draft for ACTWA review of 1980-83 Xerox agreement
  - Labor Agreement - V, 1980-1983 (Box 43, Folder 70)
    Printed copy of 1980-83 contract, copy of The Digest re approval of contract.
  - Labor Agreement, 1977-1980 (Box 43, Folder 71)
    Printed copies of 1977-1980 contract, including copy of Labor Management Relations Act.
  - Arbitration, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 72)
    Company memos and brief re arbitration case, routine correspondence.
  - ISG - Grievances and Reports (Box 43, Folder 73-76)
    Before 1979. Grievance reports from Information Systems Group
  - Labor Report - I, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 1-9)
  - Labor Report - II, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 10-20)
  - Labor Report - III, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 21-29)
  - RMG (Retromagnetic Manufacturing Group) - Grievances and Reports - I, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 30-33)
    Grievance reports from Retrographic Manufacturing Group.
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 34-38)
    Grievance reports from RMG.
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - III, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 39-42)
    Grievance reports from RMG
  - Labor Report - I, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 43-50)
  - Labor Report - II, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 51-59)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 60-67)
  - Labor Reports - I, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 68-73)
  - Labor Reports - II, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 74-79)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - I, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 80-85)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 86-90)
  - RMG - Grievances - Step 3 Monthly Summaries, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 91-93)
    Summaries of third step grievance activities [l0/80 to 1/82].
  - Arbitration, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
    Copies of arbiters' opinions and awards, Company briefs, corres from MFN to Robert J. Landsman, Office of the General Counsel of Xerox Corp., re arbitration cases t3/29/82].
  - Labor Report - I, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 6-11)
  - Labor Report - II, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 12-17)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - I, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 18-22)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 23-28)
  - Labor Report, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 29-31)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 32-35)
  - Labor Report, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 36-37)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 38-42)
  - Labor Report, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 43-44)
  - Grievances and Reports, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 45-46)
    Grievance reports.
  - Labor Report, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 47-48)
  - Grievances and Reports, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 49-50)
  - Arbitration - I, 1980-1984 (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
    Industrial Relations Grievance System chart [4/3/84], copies of grievance reports and other exhibits in arbitration cases, copy of arbiter's opinion and award.
  - Arbitration - II, 1980-1984 (Box 46, Folder 3-4)
    Opinions and awards of arbiters, drafts of Company briefs (with MFN notes).
  - Arbitration - III, 1980-1984 (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
    Opinions and awards of arbiters, briefs and exhibits of Company.
  - Arbitration - IV, 1980-1984 (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
    Opinions and awards of arbiters, briefs and exhibits of Company, memo from MFN re interpretation of agreements reached sheet for Grievance RMG 84-46 [10/25/85].
  - Arbitration - V, 1980-1984 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    Drafts of Company briefs (with MFN notes), awards and opinions of arbiters.
  - Contract, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    Printed copy of 1980-83 labor agreement between Xerox Corp. and ACTWU.
  - Contract - I, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 11-14)
    Company proposals from 1983 Company-Union contract negotiations (two copies final draft and earlier draft with notes), opening remarks of Company at negotiations (several drafts with notes), earlier proposals of Company for 1983 contract negotiations, copies of Company presentations to workers (The Choice is Ours and The Cost of Labor).
  - Contract - II, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 15-21)
    Subject index of 1983 contract negotiations minutes, minutes of Compnay-Union contract negotiation meetings [held from 12/3/82 to 3/17/83].
  - Contract - III, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 22-24)
    Subject index of 1983 contract negotiation minutes, minutes of Company-Union contract negotiation meetings [held from 3/19/83 to 3/30/83].
  - Contract - IV, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 25-30)
    Agreements reached from Company and Union contract proposals, Supplemental agreements to contract (including notes).
  - Contract - V, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 1-6)
    Working manuscript of proposed 1983-1986 contract, including agreements reached sheet.
  - ACTWA Agreement I, 1983-1986 (Box 47, Folder 7-11)
    Final manuscript of contract.
  - ACTWA Agreement II, 1983-1986 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    Printed copy of 1983-86 contract.
  - ACTWA Agreement - III, 1983-1986 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    Printed copy of 1983-86 contract including amendments adopted in 1985.
  - ACTWA Agreement - I, 1986-1989 (Box 47, Folder 14-19)
    Company proposals and Union demands, minutes of 1986 contract negotiation meetings [held from 12/17/86 to 3/15/86]
  - ACTWU Agreement - II, 1986-1989 (Box 47, Folder 20-23)
    Agreements reached at 1986 contract negotiations
  - ACTWU Agreement - III, 1986-1989 (Box 47, Folder 24)
    Summary of 1986-1989 labor agreement, two printed copies of final contract.
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports (Box 47, Folder 25)
    Before 1987. Grievance reports from RMG.
  - Labor Report, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 26-29)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 30-33)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 34-35)
  - RMG - Labor Report, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 36-37)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - I, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports - II, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 1-6)
  - RMG - Labor Report, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 7-12)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 13-18)
  - RMG - Labor Report, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 19-24)
  - Contract - I, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    Printed copy of 1989-1992 labor agreement.
  - Contract - II, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 26-27)
    Agreements reached from Company proposals.
  - Contract - III, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 28-29)
    Agreements reached from Union demands.
  - Contract - IV, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 30-38)
    Minutes of 1989 Company-Union contract negotiations (seventh meeting, pp. 113-135, missing) [held from 12/5/88 to 3/17/89].
  - ACTWU - Grievances and Reports, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 39-45)
    Grievance reports from ACTWU members at Xerox Corp
  - ACTWU - Labor Report, 1991 (Box 48, Folder 46-49)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 50-56)
  - RMG - Labor Report, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 57)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 58)
  - RMG - Labor Report - I, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 59)
  - RMG - Labor Report - II, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 60)
  - RMG - Grievances and Reports, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 61-67)
    Grievance reports from 1989-1994 (primarily from 1993 and 1994).
- Series III. ITALY FILES
  - Subject index of Italy files (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture (Box 49, Folder 2-3)
  - Art, Music, Theater (Box 49, Folder 4-5)
  - Bibliography (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Collective Bargaining and Industrial Relations (Box 49, Folder 7-9)
  - Cooperatives (Box 49, Folder 10-11)
  - Cultural Development (Box 49, Folder 12-13)
  - Economic Development (Box 49, Folder 14-17)
    Research material includes MFN notes and statistical charts of population and industry.
  - Economic Development (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
    Research material continued from previous box.
  - Education (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
  - Education - Adults and Workers (Including Training). (Box 50, Folder 6-7)
  - Education - Industrial Relations and Social Sciences. (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Italy- Employment and Unemployment (Box 50, Folder 9-10)
  - Finances and Fiscal Policy (Box 50, Folder 11-12)
  - General (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Geography and Maps (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Government (Box 50, Folder 15-16)
    Research material includes MFN notes on government expenditures from 1873-1890, and census data through 1955.
  - History (Box 50, Folder 17-20)
    Research material includes biographical notes and other historical notes.
  - Housing (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Industry - Administration (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Industry - History (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Industry - Individual Companies and Industries (Box 51, Folder 5-6)
  - Industry - Productivity and Rationalization (Box 51, Folder 7-8)
  - Industry - Structure and Organizations (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
    Includes INI, END.
  - International Affairs (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Judicial and Legal System (Box 51, Folder 12-13)
  - Labor - Agriculture (Box 51, Folder 14-15)
    Research material includes MFN notes.
  - Labor - Catholic Activities (Box 51, Folder 16-17)
  - Labor - CIGL (Box 51, Folder 18-23)
    Includes MFN notes re history, organization, and membership of CIGL.
  - Labor - CISNAL (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - Labor - Commissioni Interne, 1955-1956 (Box 51, Folder 25-26)
    Includes MFN notes regarding CI elections
  - Labor - Commissioni Interne, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
  - Labor - Commissioni Interne, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
  - Labor - General (Box 52, Folder 5-6)
    Includes MFN notes on Italian labor history.
  - Labor - Government Activities and Legislation (Box 52, Folder 7-9)
  - Labor - History (Box 52, Folder 10-12)
    Includes MFN notes on strikes and cooperative banks.
  - Labor - Independent Unions. (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Labor - Strikes. (Box 52, Folder 14-15)
  - Labor - UIL (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    Includes MFN notes on UIL organization.
  - Leadership (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
  - Literature (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
  - Planning, Conservation, Urban Development (Box 53, Folder 7-8)
  - Politics. (Box 53, Folder 9-12)
  - Population and Vital Statistics (Including Migration). (Box 53, Folder 13-14)
    Includes MFN notes.
  - Press, Radio, Television, Films (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - Religion (Box 54, Folder 3-4)
  - Science and Research (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Social Security (Box 54, Folder 6-7)
  - Social Services (Box 54, Folder 8-9)
  - Sociology, Social Thought, Social Development (Box 54, Folder 10-12)
  - Transportation and Communication (Box 54, Folder 13-14)
  - Travel and Description (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Wages, Salaries, Income, Prices, Cost-of-Living. (Box 54, Folder 16-17)
- Series IV. ARTICLES AND BOOKS
  - Sub-Series A. Publications
    - Articles, 1927-1938 (Box 55, Folder 1-4)
      (Extra Copies). Curriculum vitae of MFN, copies of "The Government Has Always Paid" (originally published in The American Scholar. vol. 4, no. 4, Autumn 1935), "Three Aspects of the Economic Life of Cincinnati, 1815 to 1840" (Ohio State Archaeological and Historical Quarterly, vol. XLIV, no. 1, Jan. 1935), "The Need for Land Use Planning from the Standpoint of Governmental Costs and Revenues: The Problem in Rural Areas" (unpublished paper), The Cost of Government in New Jersey (Trenton: New Jersey State Planning Board, 1936), and Rural Tax Delinquency in New Jersey 1929-1934 (Trenton: New Jersey State Planning Board, 1938), copies of Ohio State Archaeological and Historical Quarterly, Jan. 1935, Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society, vol. XXVII, no. 1, Apr. 1934 (containing MFN's "The White City"), Planner's Journal, Sept.-Oct. 1938 (containing MFN's "Shall Mr. Crockett Enter Planning?").
    - Articles, 1939-1945 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      (Extra Copies). Reprints of "The New York State Defense Production Plan" (Public Administration Review, vol. I, no. 5, Autumn 1941).
    - AFL-CIO Merger, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
      Early drafts of "The Structure and Government of the AFL-CIO" (Industrial and Labor Relations Review, vol. 9, no. 3, Apr. 1956), routine correspondence re revisions of article, and copies of Apr. 1956 ILR Review.
    - AFL-CIO Merger - Clippings (Box 55, Folder 8)
      Newspaper clippings and MFN notes re AFL and CIO merger.
    - AFL-CIO Merger - Documents, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      Material re 1955 AFL and CIO merger.
    - American Experience in Military Government., 1948 (Box 55, Folder 10-11)
      Corres between MFN, George Benson, and Carl Friedrich re American Experiences in Military Government in World War II (New York: Rhinehart & Company, 1948), drafts and revisions of MFN's chapter, "American Military Government in Italy."
    - Annals - Italian Labor - Correspondence., 1957 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      Corres re "The Italian Labor Movement in 1956: The Structure of Crisis" (published in The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, vol. 310, March 1957).
    - Annals - Italian Labor - Reprints, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 13)
      Copies of March 1957 Annals.
    - Bibliography, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 14)
      Copies of A Bibliography of American Labor Union History (Bibliography Series No. 2, NYSSILR, Cornell Univ., May 1958. Reissued Oct. 1960).
    - Bibliography - Comments (Box 55, Folder 15)
      Corres re MFN's Bibliography.
    - Bibliography - Distribution (Box 55, Folder 16)
      Corres re distribution and sales of Bibliography.
    - Bibliography - News Releases (Box 55, Folder 17)
      News releases re 1958 Bibliography.
    - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 18)
      Comments. Comments and notices re MFN's A Representative Bibliography of American Labor History (Bibliography Series No. 6, NYSSILR, Cornell Univ., 1964).
    - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 19)
      Corrections. Corrections of citations in 1964 Bibliography.
    - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 20)
      Correspondence. Routine correspondence.
    - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 21)
      Distribution. Corres and lists re distribution and sales of 1964 Bibliography.
    - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 22-26)
      Manuscript. Copy of manuscript of 1964 Bibliography, including index and MFN notes.
    - Bibliography, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 27-29)
      Publicity. News releases and promotional brochures for 1964 Bibliography, copies of printed manuscript.
    - Diritto del Lavaro - Comments, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Comments re MFN's "Appunti sul funzionamento delle commissioni interne" (Il Diritto del Lavaro. no. 6, Nov.-Dec. 1956). Includes newspaper clippings.
    - Diritto del Lavaro - Distribution (Box 56, Folder 2)
      Routine corres re distribution of Diritto article
    - Diritto del Lavaro - Manuscript 1. (Box 56, Folder 3-4)
      Early draft of Diritto article (in Italian) including MFN notes and charts.
    - Diritto del Lavaro - Manuscript 2., 1953-1956 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      Drafts of unpublished English condensation of Diritto article ("The Operation of Grievance Committees in Italy: 1953-1956"), routine correspondence.
    - Diritto del Lavaro - Reprints (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Reprints of Diritto article and English condensation
    - Grievance Committees in Italy - Activities and Organizations (Box 56, Folder 7)
      Material (in Italian) re activities of commissioni interne (grievance committees), a notebook with MFN notes re activities and organization of CI.
    - Grievance Committees in Italy - Comments. (Box 56, Folder 8)
      Notices, reviews, and comments re MFN's Labor Unions and National Politics in Italian Industrial Plants (Institute of International Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell Univ., 1954).
    - Grievance Committees in Italy - Contracts, 1943-1953 (Box 56, Folder 9-10)
      Material re the establishment and function of Italian grievance committees, copies of Italian union contracts, MFN notes re contracts. Includes newspaper clippings.
    - Grievance Committees in Italy - Corrections (Box 56, Folder 11)
      Corres re revisions and updating of Labor Unions manuscript.
    - Grievance Committees in Italy - Correspondence (Box 56, Folder 12)